<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
        xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
        xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
        xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
        xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
        xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
        xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
>
	<channel>
		<title>ENGINE Online</title>
				<atom:link href="https://engine.online/feed/availability" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<link>https://engine.online</link>
		<description>ENGINE Online News</description>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 22:52:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<language>el-gr</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
		<image>
			<title>ENGINE Online</title>
			<url>https://engine.online/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/Engine_Logo-black-copy-1-1.png</url>
			<link>https://engine.online</link>
			<description>ENGINE Online</description>
		</image>
				<item>
				<title>Europe &amp; Africa Fuel Availability Outlook 12 Nov 2025</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Algeciras]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Amsterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Antwerp]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Barcelona]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Ceuta]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Durban]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Gibraltar]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Gothenburg]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Hamburg]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Istanbul]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Lagos]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Las Palmas]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Lisbon]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Lome]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Malta Offshore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Piraeus]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Port Louis]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Richards Bay]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Rotterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Sao Tome]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Skaw]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Walvis Bay]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[ULSFO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[Prompt supplies are tight in the Gibraltar StraitWeak HSFO demand in IstanbulReduced lead times at Nigeria’s Lagos anchorageIMAGE: Aerial view of the Bay of Gibraltar.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="ql-font-titlebullets">Prompt supplies are tight in the Gibraltar Strait</span></p><p><span class="ql-font-titlebullets">Weak HSFO demand in Istanbul</span></p><p><span class="ql-font-titlebullets">Reduced lead times at Nigeria’s Lagos anchorage</span></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/b3e833f7-2d96-49f5-81bf-c66d2f65078c-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/b3e833f7-2d96-49f5-81bf-c66d2f65078c-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/b3e833f7-2d96-49f5-81bf-c66d2f65078c-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="b3e833f7-2d96-49f5-81bf-c66d2f65078c-600w.jpg,b3e833f7-2d96-49f5-81bf-c66d2f65078c-1200w.jpg"/><em class="ql-font-caption">IMAGE: Aerial view of the Bay of Gibraltar. Getty Images</em></p><p><br/></p><p><strong>Northwest Europe</strong></p><p>Fuel availability has improved slightly in the ARA bunkering hub, but prompt supplies remain tight for all fuel grades. Buyers are advised to book around 5-7 days ahead to get competitive offers from a wider selection of suppliers, a trader told ENGINE. </p><p>The ARA’s independently held fuel oil stocks have jumped by 14% in November so far, according to Insights Global data.﻿ Meanwhile, the region’s independent gasoil inventories - which include diesel and heating oil – have slipped by 2% in November, compared to October, according to the data.</p><p>Bunker deliveries of all fuel types in Germany’s Hamburg require around 3-5 days of notice, a trader told ENGINE. </p><p>Off Denmark’s Skaw and in Sweden’s Gothenburg, deliveries of all fuel grades require at least 10 days of lead time, a trader said.</p><p><strong>Mediterranean</strong></p><p>Fuel availability is normal in Gibraltar Strait ports, amid strong demand. Immediate deliveries of all fuel grades are challenging, with VLSFO and LSMGO supplies requiring around a week of notice, a trader said. HSFO lead times have been slightly reduced to 7-10 days this week, compared to last week when most suppliers said they needed at least two weeks of lead time, the trader added. </p><p>Some suppliers in Gibraltar now face around two days of delays, compared to last week when some suppliers were running just 4-6 hours behind schedule, port agent MH Bland said. In neighbouring Algeciras, some suppliers continue to operate almost a day behind schedule, while all suppliers are running on time in Ceuta, port agent MH Bland said.</p><p>Southwesterly wind gusts of between 25-40 knots and westerly waves of up to 2 metres are forecast in Gibraltar Strait ports between 14-15 November, which may disrupt bunker operations.</p><p>Supplies in Las Palmas are also tight for prompt dates, but lead times have improved, with most suppliers requiring around 5-7 days for VLSFO and LSMGO deliveries and around 10 days for HSFO, a trader told ENGINE. Last week, one supplier required around two weeks of lead time for all deliveries. </p><p>Adverse weather conditions are forecast in Las Palmas in the coming days. Waves of around 2 metres are forecast intermittently between 13-21 November. This may suspend of all bunker operations at the port's outer anchorage. During such suspensions, deliveries might still be able to be carried out at the inner anchorage and at berth, but may face some delays due to lack of space. </p><p>In Spain’s Barcelona, all deliveries need around 5-7 days of notice, a trader said.</p><p>Availability is normal in Portugal’s Lisbon, with buyers are advised to give 3-5-day notice, a local supplier told ENGINE. </p><p>Supplies are proceeding normally off Malta, with a 2-4 day notice enough for supplies of HSFO, ULSFO, LSMGO and VLSFO fuel grades, a trader told ENGINE. Strong southerly wind gusts of between 25-30 knots and high waves are forecast between 18-19 November, which may suspend bunkering. </p><p>In Greece’s Piraeus, buyers are advised to give a lead time of around 3-4 days for deliveries of all fuel grades to avoid paying a premium, a trader said.</p><p>In Istanbul, ULSFO, VLSFO and LSMGO supplies are stable and available promptly, with a notice of 1-5 days advised. HSFO availability is very tight, a local supplier said.</p><p><strong>Africa</strong></p><p>Prompt VLSFO and LSMGO availability remains tight in the Togolese port of Lome and off Namibia’s Walvis Bay. Most suppliers advise lead times of around 5-7 days in both locations, a trader said. HSFO availability is very tight in both locations, with suppliers struggling to load cargoes, the trader added. </p><p>At Nigeria’s Lagos anchorage, recommended VLSFO and LSMGO lead times have come down to around five days, from 10-14 days last week, a source told ENGINE.</p><p>LSMGO availability is normal in Sao Tome and supplies are available on a prompt basis, a local supplier told ENGINE.</p><p>In South Africa’s Durban and Richards Bay, HSFO availability is tighter than for VLSFO, with the former requiring around a week of lead time, compared to just 2-3-day notice required for VLSFO, a trader said. &nbsp;</p><p>At least six vessels are expected to call for bunkers in Durban between 14-19 November, Transnet National Port Authority said.&nbsp;</p><p>Transnet National has issued a weather warning for 13 November, when southerly wind gusts of more than 25 knots and waves of more than 3 metres are forecast, which could suspend bunkering. Rough weather is forecast intermittently until Saturday evening. </p><p>In Mauritius’ Port Louis, HSFO supplies could require a lead time of around 14 days, while VLSFO and LSMGO supplies can be carried out with a notice of around 5-7 days, a trader said. </p><p><em>By Nachiket Tekawade</em></p><p><em>Please get in touch with comments or additional info to news@engine.online</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/europe-and-africa-fuel-availability-outlook-12-nov-2025-73c8</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/europe-and-africa-fuel-availability-outlook-12-nov-2025-73c8</guid>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>FIS: Fuel Oil Report 12 Nov 2025</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Rotterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/55470555-87ff-4db2-95f2-72b643e908b6-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/55470555-87ff-4db2-95f2-72b643e908b6-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/55470555-87ff-4db2-95f2-72b643e908b6-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="55470555-87ff-4db2-95f2-72b643e908b6-600w.jpg,55470555-87ff-4db2-95f2-72b643e908b6-1200w.jpg"//></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/f49bdc8a-bdf0-4589-82a7-8bf087a93d06-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/f49bdc8a-bdf0-4589-82a7-8bf087a93d06-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/f49bdc8a-bdf0-4589-82a7-8bf087a93d06-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="f49bdc8a-bdf0-4589-82a7-8bf087a93d06-600w.jpg,f49bdc8a-bdf0-4589-82a7-8bf087a93d06-1200w.jpg"//></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-12-nov-2025-73c5</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-12-nov-2025-73c5</guid>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>Nolu Energy launches bunkering services for yachts in Tunisia</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Bizerte]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Gabes]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Sfax]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Tunis]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[Marine fuels trader Nolu Energy has started offering bunkering services to yachts calling at major Tunisian ports, the company’s owner Kenni Goldenbeck said in a LinkedIn post.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="ql-font-standfirst">Marine fuels trader Nolu Energy has started offering bunkering services to yachts calling at major Tunisian ports, the company’s owner Kenni Goldenbeck said in a LinkedIn post. </span></p><p><img class="img-fluid" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/8608edb2-e3ef-45fb-a104-be0a71cf333d-600w.jpg" data-filenames="8608edb2-e3ef-45fb-a104-be0a71cf333d-600w.jpg"/><em><span class="ql-cursor">﻿</span></em></p><p><em>IMAGE: Yachts moored to a pier at El Kantaoui, Tunisia. Getty Images</em></p><p>The company will supply marine gasoil to yachts visiting all major ports in the North African country, including Bizerte, Tunis, Gabes and Sfax. </p><p>“Tunisia has become an increasingly popular stop for yachts traveling from France and Spain mainly, and we’re ready to ensure smooth, efficient, and reliable fuel deliveries along the way,” Goldenbeck said.</p><p>The company will also be equipped to psupply  lubricants, full agency service and spare parts through local partners. </p><p><br/></p><p><em>By Nachiket Tekawade</em></p><p><em>Please get in touch with comments or additional info to news@engine.online</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/nolu-energy-launches-bunkering-services-for-yachts-in-tunisia-73c1</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/nolu-energy-launches-bunkering-services-for-yachts-in-tunisia-73c1</guid>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:50:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>East of Suez Fuel Availability Outlook 11 Nov 2025</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Auckland]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Basra]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Busan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Cairns]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Chiba]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Colombo]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Daesan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Dalian]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Dampier]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Darwin]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Djibouti]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Duqm]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Fremantle]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Fujairah]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Fuzhou]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Guangzhou]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Hambantota]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Hong Kong]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Hualien]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Jeddah]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Kaohsiung]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Kawasaki]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Keelung]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Khor Fakkan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Kobe]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Kwinana]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Marsden Point]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Mizushima]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Muscat]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Nagoya]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Oita]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Onsan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Osaka]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Port Kembla]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Port Klang]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Port Suez]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Portland]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Qingdao]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Ras Laffan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Salalah]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Shanghai]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Sohar]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Sydney]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Taichung]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Tauranga]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Tianjin]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Tokyo]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Ulsan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Wellington]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Welshpool]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Xiamen]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Yangpu]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Yeosu]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Yokkaichi]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Yokohama]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Zhoushan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO B-30]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[VLSFO and LSMGO availability good in Port KlangBunkering remains suspended in some Zhoushan anchoragesBunker demand low in FujairahIMAGE: Industrial cargo ships in Busan port area, South Korea.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="ql-font-titlebullets">VLSFO and LSMGO availability good in Port Klang</span></p><p><span class="ql-font-titlebullets">Bunkering remains suspended in some Zhoushan anchorages</span></p><p><span class="ql-font-titlebullets">Bunker demand low in Fujairah</span></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/498a6e51-abdb-4c9c-88f3-36285893b14d-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/498a6e51-abdb-4c9c-88f3-36285893b14d-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/498a6e51-abdb-4c9c-88f3-36285893b14d-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="498a6e51-abdb-4c9c-88f3-36285893b14d-600w.jpg,498a6e51-abdb-4c9c-88f3-36285893b14d-1200w.jpg"/><em class="ql-font-caption">IMAGE: Industrial cargo ships in Busan port area, South Korea. Getty Images</em></p><p><strong>﻿<br/>Singapore and Malaysia</strong></p><p>Despite subdued bunker demand in Singapore, VLSFO delivery times now show a wide disparity among suppliers — some can supply within three days, while others need up to 12 days. Last week, most suppliers quoted lead times of 5–10 days.</p><p>HSFO supply has tightened slightly, with lead times stretching from 5–10 days last week to 7–12 days now. In contrast, LSMGO availability has improved, with current lead times of 3–10 days, down from 5–17 days previously.</p><p>Residual fuel oil inventories at the port have averaged 1% higher in the first week of November compared to October levels, remaining above 24 million bbls. This comes despite a 1% fall in net fuel oil imports, which have dropped by 1.22 million bbls, while exports have also decreased by 1.19 million bbls, according to Enterprise Singapore.</p><p>Meanwhile, middle distillate stocks have averaged 3% lower over the same period.</p><p>At Malaysia’s Port Klang, VLSFO and LSMGO remain readily available, with prompt deliveries possible for smaller parcels, though HSFO supply continues to be tight.</p><p><strong>East Asia</strong></p><p>Bunker demand in Zhoushan remains muted, with most suppliers now advising lead times of 4–6 days for VLSFO, slightly shorter than last week’s 5–8 days. HSFO lead times have also narrowed to 4–6 days, while LSMGO remains steady within the same range.</p><p>However, bunker deliveries at Zhoushan’s Xiushandong anchorage were suspended on Monday due to severe weather linked to Tropical Storm Fung-wong, according to a source. Operations at the outer Tiaozhoumen and Xiazhimen anchorages have been halted since the weekend, though bunkering at the inner Mazhi anchorage continues uninterrupted. </p><p>Most suppliers remain unsure regarding when full operations will resume, as the storm tracks north-northeast toward Taiwan.</p><p>Fuel availability varies widely across northern China. Dalian and Qingdao have adequate VLSFO and LSMGO stocks, though HSFO remains tight in Qingdao. Tianjin, meanwhile, continues to experience shortages across all grades. In Shanghai, supplies of VLSFO and HSFO are limited, while LSMGO remains relatively stable.</p><p>Further south, Fuzhou is facing shortages in both VLSFO and LSMGO, while Xiamen has sufficient VLSFO but restricted LSMGO availability. Delivery options for both fuels remain limited in Yangpu and Guangzhou.</p><p>In Hong Kong, lead times across all grades are around seven days, consistent with recent weeks.</p><p>Meanwhile, Taiwan’s Central Weather Administration (CWA) has issued a land warning for Tropical Storm Fung-wong, whose center was located 370 km southwest of Eluanbi. The warning applies to Kaohsiung, Tainan, Taitung County, and Pingtung County, while a sea warning remains in effect for the Bashi Channel, Dongsha Island, southeast Taiwan waters, and the Taiwan Strait.</p><p>As a result, bunkering at Kaohsiung has been suspended today, and Taichung deliveries were temporarily halted this morning. Operations at Keelung and Hualien are still running smoothly, though traders caution that disruptions could follow.</p><p>At present, VLSFO and LSMGO can typically be delivered within three days at Keelung, Taichung, Hualien, and Kaohsiung, with little change from last week.</p><p>Bunker demand in South Korea remains low, with lead times across all fuel grades holding at around 2–9 days, nearly unchanged from 3–8 days last week. However, adverse weather is expected to disrupt operations — between 17–18 November in Busan and Ulsan, and from 16–18 and 20 November in Yeosu and Daesan, a trader said.</p><p>In Japan, prompt VLSFO supply remains tight across key ports including Tokyo, Chiba, Yokohama, Kawasaki, Osaka, Kobe, Sakai, Mizushima, Nagoya, and Yokkaichi. LSMGO stocks are generally adequate nationwide, though immediate deliveries are proving difficult in Mizushima.</p><p>B24-VLSFO is available only on request in Tokyo, Chiba, Kawasaki, and Yokohama. Meanwhile, HSFO availability has tightened across most Japanese ports, and Oita has shortages of all fuel grades, including VLSFO, LSMGO, and HSFO.</p><p><strong>Oceania</strong></p><p>In Western Australia, VLSFO and LSMGO remain readily available at Kwinana and Fremantle, with most suppliers quoting lead times of around seven days. Deliveries are primarily handled by barge from a single supplier, while LSMGO can also be delivered by truck. However, strong afternoon winds occasionally cause bunkering delays, a source noted.</p><p>In New South Wales, VLSFO is available at Port Kembla through both truck and pipeline, with a minimum pipeline delivery of 70 mt and smaller volumes supplied by truck. </p><p>In Sydney, a single barge operates alongside truck and pipeline options at selected berths, though its schedule can be affected by naval and cruise liner movements. VLSFO and LSMGO stocks remain ample, while HSFO supply is limited. Suppliers typically recommend lead times of about seven days. </p><p>The expected increase in cruise activity between December and February in Sydney, Cairns, and Darwin could further affect vessel schedules.</p><p>In Queensland, VLSFO and LSMGO are easily accessible at Brisbane and Gladstone, both with lead times of around seven days. HSFO in Brisbane is available only on request, while Gladstone may experience occasional weather-related delays. Access to Brisbane’s AAT terminal remains challenging. The port now operates two barges under separate suppliers, both supplying VLSFO and LSMGO, with HSFO available upon enquiry.</p><p>In Victoria, the ports of Melbourne and Geelong continue to maintain strong VLSFO and LSMGO inventories, though HSFO remains tight, especially for prompt deliveries. Melbourne, however, currently holds adequate HSFO reserves. Both ports are served by a single barge, and adverse weather in the Bass Strait can cause occasional delays. A seven-day lead time is generally advised. LSMGO can also be trucked to smaller ports such as Portland and Port Welshpool, with deliveries taking 2–3 days.</p><p>Overall, bunker supply across Australian ports remains stable, typically requiring around seven days’ notice. Thanks to ample inventories, deliveries within 3–4 days are often possible. Ports equipped with pipeline infrastructure, including Darwin and Dampier, still partly depend on truck deliveries.</p><p>In New Zealand, bunker availability remains steady, with VLSFO widely supplied at Tauranga and Auckland. Tauranga offers pipeline access at select berths, while Marsden Point can deliver both VLSFO and LSMGO via pipeline to cargo vessels.&nbsp;</p><p>Yesterday, strong winds in Wellington caused temporary bunkering delays. Looking ahead, the cyclone season in northern Australia — from 1 November to 30 April — is expected to periodically disrupt bunkering schedules, a source cautioned.</p><p><strong>South Asia</strong></p><p>In Sri Lanka, a supplier is advising prompt lead times of 1–2 days for all grades at both Colombo and Hambantota, slightly shorter than the three days quoted last week.</p><p><strong>Middle East</strong></p><p>Prompt bunker supply remains tight across all fuel grades in Fujairah, as several suppliers continue to grapple with low inventories and loading delays, despite muted demand. Lead times of 5–7 days are generally recommended, mirroring conditions at the nearby Khor Fakkan port. Some suppliers can still arrange urgent deliveries, though typically at a premium, a source said.</p><p>In Iraq’s Basrah, VLSFO and LSMGO remain readily available, while HSFO continues to be in short supply.</p><p>Saudi Arabia’s Jeddah has seen improved availability of both VLSFO and LSMGO, though port congestion continues to slow operations.</p><p>In stark contrast, Egypt’s Port Suez is facing severe shortages, with VLSFO, LSMGO, and HSFO stocks nearly depleted. Similarly, Qatar’s Ras Laffan is reporting tight VLSFO and LSMGO availability, while Djibouti is under acute supply pressure, with VLSFO and HSFO almost exhausted and LSMGO running critically low.</p><p>Meanwhile, Oman’s ports — Sohar, Salalah, Muscat, and Duqm — continue to maintain a steady LSMGO supply, with prompt dates available.</p><p><em>By Tuhin Roy</em></p><p><em>Please get in touch with comments or additional info to news@engine.online</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/east-of-suez-fuel-availability-outlook-11-nov-2025-73bb</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/east-of-suez-fuel-availability-outlook-11-nov-2025-73bb</guid>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 13:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>FIS: Fuel Oil Report 11 Nov 2025</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Rotterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/672e5eef-18ea-4171-8445-b90c5125780d-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/672e5eef-18ea-4171-8445-b90c5125780d-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/672e5eef-18ea-4171-8445-b90c5125780d-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="672e5eef-18ea-4171-8445-b90c5125780d-600w.jpg,672e5eef-18ea-4171-8445-b90c5125780d-1200w.jpg"//></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/b65ff25b-3c73-464a-a8b5-6549ec1d179d-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/b65ff25b-3c73-464a-a8b5-6549ec1d179d-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/b65ff25b-3c73-464a-a8b5-6549ec1d179d-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="b65ff25b-3c73-464a-a8b5-6549ec1d179d-600w.jpg,b65ff25b-3c73-464a-a8b5-6549ec1d179d-1200w.jpg"//></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-11-nov-2025-73ba</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-11-nov-2025-73ba</guid>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 12:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>ATH Trading bolsters Angolan bunkering fleet with new tanker</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Luanda]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[MGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[Madrid-headquartered ATH Trading has expanded its bunkering operations in Angola with the addition of a new 5,000 mt capacity tanker, the ATH Catamba.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="ql-font-standfirst">Madrid-headquartered ATH Trading has expanded its bunkering operations in Angola with the addition of a new 5,000 mt capacity tanker, the ATH Catamba. </span></p><p><img class="img-fluid" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/929184ad-62d0-4ece-a965-a3386653c4fb-600w.jpg" data-filenames="929184ad-62d0-4ece-a965-a3386653c4fb-600w.jpg"/><em class="ql-font-caption">IMAGE: ATH Trading’s bunker tanker ATH Catamba. ATH Trading</em></p><p><br/>The vessel is equipped to supply VLSFO and MGO grades, the company announced in a LinkedIn post.</p><p>“This vessel marks a significant step in our long-term strategy to enhance Angola’s bunkering infrastructure and expand our role as a committed local physical supplier. From ship to shore, we’re fully engaged,” it said.</p><p>With the <em>ATH Catamba</em>, ATH Trading now operates two bunker tankers in Angola, following the <em>ATH Lemba</em>, which joined the fleet in 2022.</p><p>Founded in 2021, ATH Trading provides bunkering services in Luanda and other major Angolan ports, supplying to vessels involved in offshore, fishing, and cargo operations, according to its website.</p><p><em>By Tuhin Roy</em></p><p><em>Please get in touch with comments or additional info to news@engine.online</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/ath-trading-bolsters-angolan-bunkering-fleet-with-new-tanker-73b4</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/ath-trading-bolsters-angolan-bunkering-fleet-with-new-tanker-73b4</guid>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>FIS: Fuel Oil Report 10 Nov 2025</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Rotterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/01aed99e-4c64-4eac-aa41-d6b3126f13a7-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/01aed99e-4c64-4eac-aa41-d6b3126f13a7-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/01aed99e-4c64-4eac-aa41-d6b3126f13a7-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="01aed99e-4c64-4eac-aa41-d6b3126f13a7-600w.jpg,01aed99e-4c64-4eac-aa41-d6b3126f13a7-1200w.jpg"//></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/99844425-efd1-4885-b828-024ae254a65b-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/99844425-efd1-4885-b828-024ae254a65b-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/99844425-efd1-4885-b828-024ae254a65b-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="99844425-efd1-4885-b828-024ae254a65b-600w.jpg,99844425-efd1-4885-b828-024ae254a65b-1200w.jpg"//></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-10-nov-2025-73a6</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-10-nov-2025-73a6</guid>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>ARA fuel oil stocks surge 14% in November thus far</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Amsterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Antwerp]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Rotterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[ULSFO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[Independently held fuel oil stocks in ARA have jumped by 14% in November so far, according to Insights Global data.﻿Changes in monthly average ARA stocks from October to November (so far):Fuel oil stocks up 800,000 bbls to 6.68 million bblsGasoil stocks down 270,000 bbls to 16.49 million bblsFuel oil stocks have significantly ticked up from last month, when the lowest monthly average in this year was recorded.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="ql-font-standfirst">Independently held fuel oil stocks in ARA have jumped by 14% in November so far, according to Insights Global data.﻿</span></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/f96e7904-b5a1-422a-b821-47beac555fbc-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/f96e7904-b5a1-422a-b821-47beac555fbc-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/f96e7904-b5a1-422a-b821-47beac555fbc-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="f96e7904-b5a1-422a-b821-47beac555fbc-600w.jpg,f96e7904-b5a1-422a-b821-47beac555fbc-1200w.jpg"//></p><p><br//>Changes in monthly average ARA stocks from October to November (so far):</p><ul><li><strong>Fuel oil stocks up 800,000 bbls to 6.68 million bbls</strong></li><li><strong>Gasoil stocks down 270,000 bbls to 16.49 million bbls</strong></li></ul><p>Fuel oil stocks have significantly ticked up from last month, when the lowest monthly average in this year was recorded. </p><p>Meanwhile, the region’s independent gasoil inventories - which include diesel and heating oil – have slipped by 2% in November so far, compared to October, according to the data.</p><p>Prompt supply for all fuel types is tight in the ARA hub this week, with buyers advised to book at least a week in advance for a wider selection of suppliers, a trader told ENGINE.</p><p><em>By Nachiket Tekawade</em></p><p><em>Please get in touch with comments or additional info to news@engine.online</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/ara-fuel-oil-stocks-surge-14-pc-in-november-7399</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/ara-fuel-oil-stocks-surge-14-pc-in-november-7399</guid>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>FIS: Fuel Oil Report 7 Nov 2025</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Rotterdam]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/1afa2479-a480-4909-b5cf-b83dc50d9aac-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/1afa2479-a480-4909-b5cf-b83dc50d9aac-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/1afa2479-a480-4909-b5cf-b83dc50d9aac-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="1afa2479-a480-4909-b5cf-b83dc50d9aac-600w.jpg,1afa2479-a480-4909-b5cf-b83dc50d9aac-1200w.jpg"//></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/d40b87ff-ddf6-421b-bc63-23e3c9a23c28-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/d40b87ff-ddf6-421b-bc63-23e3c9a23c28-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/d40b87ff-ddf6-421b-bc63-23e3c9a23c28-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="d40b87ff-ddf6-421b-bc63-23e3c9a23c28-600w.jpg,d40b87ff-ddf6-421b-bc63-23e3c9a23c28-1200w.jpg"//></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-7-nov-2025-739a</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/fis-fuel-oil-report-7-nov-2025-739a</guid>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>East of Suez Market Update 7 Nov 2025</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Fujairah]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Klang]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[Zhoushan]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO B-30]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO B-30]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[Conventional fuel prices in East of Suez ports have moved in mixed directions, and VLSFO and LSMGO availability is good in Malaysia’s Port Klang.IMAGE: An old wooden cargo ship setting out from Port Klang.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="ql-font-standfirst">Conventional fuel prices in East of Suez ports have moved in mixed directions, and VLSFO and LSMGO availability is good in Malaysia’s Port Klang.</span></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/05970d12-8468-46a8-a4fe-594ffed203c8-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/05970d12-8468-46a8-a4fe-594ffed203c8-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/05970d12-8468-46a8-a4fe-594ffed203c8-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="05970d12-8468-46a8-a4fe-594ffed203c8-600w.jpg,05970d12-8468-46a8-a4fe-594ffed203c8-1200w.jpg"/><em class="ql-font-caption">IMAGE: An old wooden cargo ship setting out from Port Klang. Getty Images</em></p><p><br/>Changes on the day to 17.00 SGT (09.00 GMT) today:</p><ul><li>VLSFO prices up in Fujairah ($2/mt) and Singapore ($1/mt), and unchanged in Zhoushan</li><li>LSMGO prices up in Zhoushan ($12/mt) and Fujairah ($1/mt), and down Singapore ($1/mt)</li><li>HSFO prices up in Zhoushan ($3/mt), unchanged in Fujairah, and down in Singapore ($1/mt)</li></ul><p>Zhoushan's LSMGO price has recorded the steepest gains across the three main Asian bunker hubs in the past session. <span style="background-color: rgb(47, 47, 47);">A higher-priced 50-150 mt stem, fixed at $723/mt, may have supported the price.</span></p><p><span style="background-color: rgb(47, 47, 47);">At the Chinese port, LSMGO lead times have slightly increased to 3–6 days from 2–4 days last week, according to a trader.</span></p><p>Over at Singapore, LSMGO deliveries are now inconsistent, as several suppliers face tight loading schedules and limited stocks. Lead times now range between 5–17 days, up from last week’s shorter span of 4–9 days.</p><p>On the other hand, VLSFO supply has improved, with lead times averaging 5–10 days — a clear improvement from last week’s uneven range of four days to nearly two weeks. HSFO availability has also strengthened, with lead times reduced to 5–10 days from the previous 6–11 days.</p><p>At Malaysia’s Port Klang, VLSFO and LSMGO remain readily available, and prompt deliveries are possible for smaller volumes, though HSFO supply remains limited.</p><p><strong>Brent</strong></p><p>The front-month ICE Brent contract has lost by $0.16/bbl on the day, to trade at $64.07/bbl at 17.00 SGT (09.00 GMT) today.</p><p><strong>Upward pressure:</strong></p><p>Brent crude has held some ground this week amid concerns of potential supply disruptions, as Western nations continue to tighten sanctions on Russia.</p><p>In October, the US Treasury Department’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) sanctioned Rosneft and Lukoil, along with 34 of their subsidiaries.</p><p>Rosneft and Lukoil are Russia’s two largest oil producers, producing around 50% of the country’s total oil production, according to ING Bank’s head of commodities strategy, Warren Patterson.</p><p>“Successfully restricting these flows could dramatically change the outlook for the oil market,” Patterson said.</p><p><strong>Downward pressure:</strong></p><p>Eight members of the OPEC+ coalition have collectively decided to increase supply again by 137,000 b/d in December, marking the eighth consecutive month that the Saudi Arabia-led group has planned to hike production.</p><p>Saudi Arabia will produce around 10.1 million b/d in December – largely matching November’s figures. Russia will produce 9.6 million b/d, while Iraq and the UAE will produce 4.3 million b/d and 3.4 million b/d respectively, the OPEC secretariat said.</p><p>The decision has put downward pressure on Brent’s price, as signals of further supply additions typically pressure the market in an already oversupplied environment.</p><p>“For now, our balance sheet continues to show a significant surplus in 2026, which should keep downward pressure on prices,” Patterson added.</p><p><em>By Tuhin Roy, Samantha Shaji and Aparupa Mazumder</em></p><p><em>Please get in touch with comments or additional info to news@engine.online</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/east-of-suez-market-update-7-nov-2025-7396</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/east-of-suez-market-update-7-nov-2025-7396</guid>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:13:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
					<item>
				<title>Singapore’s fuel oil inventories inch up 1% coming into November</title>
				<category>Availability</category>
								<category><![CDATA[Singapore]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[HSFO380]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[LSMGO]]></category>
								<category><![CDATA[VLSFO]]></category>
								<description><![CDATA[Singapore’s residual fuel oil stocks have averaged 1% higher in the first week of November than across October, Enterprise Singapore’s latest data shows.Changes in monthly average Singapore stocks from October to November (so far):Residual fuel oil stocks up 350,000 bbls to 24.48 million bblsMiddle distillate stocks down 260,000 bbls to 9.22 million bblsSingapore’s fuel oil inventories have remained above 24 million bbls, despite a 1% drop in the port’s net fuel oil imports so far this month.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="ql-font-standfirst">Singapore’s residual fuel oil stocks have averaged 1% higher in the first week of November than across October, Enterprise Singapore’s latest data shows.</span></p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/8ae02cae-258f-4b94-b00b-d9e4c6e8b483-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/8ae02cae-258f-4b94-b00b-d9e4c6e8b483-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/8ae02cae-258f-4b94-b00b-d9e4c6e8b483-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="8ae02cae-258f-4b94-b00b-d9e4c6e8b483-600w.jpg,8ae02cae-258f-4b94-b00b-d9e4c6e8b483-1200w.jpg"/></p><p><br/>Changes in monthly average Singapore stocks from October to November (so far):</p><ul><li>Residual fuel oil stocks up 350,000 bbls to 24.48 million bbls</li><li>Middle distillate stocks down 260,000 bbls to 9.22 million bbls</li></ul><p>Singapore’s fuel oil inventories have remained above 24 million bbls, despite a 1% drop in the port’s net fuel oil imports so far this month. Imports have decreased by 1.22 million bbls, while exports have declined by 1.19 million bbls. </p><p>Meanwhile, middle distillate stocks at the port have averaged 3% lower during the same period.</p><p><img class="img-fluid" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 600px, 1200px" srcset="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/1652bc30-2972-4c18-8c2a-202fe899f768-600w.jpg 600w, https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/1652bc30-2972-4c18-8c2a-202fe899f768-1200w.jpg 1200w" src="https://trade.engine.online/blobs/news/1652bc30-2972-4c18-8c2a-202fe899f768-1200w.jpg" data-filenames="1652bc30-2972-4c18-8c2a-202fe899f768-600w.jpg,1652bc30-2972-4c18-8c2a-202fe899f768-1200w.jpg"/></p><p><br/>Changes in Singapore fuel oil trade from October to November (so far):</p><ul><li>Fuel oil imports down 1.22 million bbls to 4.53 million bbls</li><li>Fuel oil exports down 1.19 million bbls to 1.54 million bbls</li><li>Fuel oil net imports down 29,000 bbls to 3 million bbls</li></ul><p>Bunker demand in Singapore has stayed muted this week, a source said. </p><p>VLSFO supply has improved, with lead times averaging 5–10 days — a clear improvement from last week’s uneven range of four days to nearly two weeks. HSFO availability has also strengthened, with lead times reduced to 5–10 days from the previous 6–11 days. </p><p>However, LSMGO deliveries have turned more inconsistent, as several suppliers face tight loading schedules and limited stocks. Lead times for LSMGO now range between 5–17 days, up from last week’s shorter span of 4–9 days.</p><p><em>By Tuhin Roy</em></p><p><em>Please get in touch with comments or additional info to news@engine.online</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
				<link>https://engine.online/news/availability/singapores-fuel-oil-inventories-inch-up-1-pc-coming-into-november-7394</link>
				<guid>https://engine.online/news/availability/singapores-fuel-oil-inventories-inch-up-1-pc-coming-into-november-7394</guid>
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 07:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<source url="https://engine.online">ENGINE Online</source>
			</item>
			</channel>
</rss>
